LUKAS EINLER LARSSON

17st Aug 1999 • Gothenburg, Sweden

in lukas-einler-larsson

Cybersecurity of remote work migration

Itggot-lukas-einlerlarsson

PROFILE

I am a curious and ambitious problem solver based in Gothenburg, Sweden. I studied IT-security and software development at Bleking Tekniska Högskola in Karlskrona, Blekinge. Me and my classmate's bachelor thesis has been published to the journal "Journal of Information Security and Applications"; Elsevier publishing.

EMPLOYMENT

Developer / DevSecOps Engineer

SAAB Q Gothenburg, Sweden

Aug 2023 - Ongoing

- Worked in an IT compartment called Software Factory, mainly working with developing and setting up CI/CD pipelines and servers.
- This job gave me lots of knowledge about linux, bash scripting and linux software.
- Designed (with Plant UML) and developed a program in python that continuously searched for updates and transferred updated git and artifactory data to different security environments within SAAB.
- Worked with small webservers (python-flask) to setup api's between systems and I have created e.g. a Mattermost bot. I have also worked with certifications and reverse proxies such as NGINX.
- Used docker/podman and docker compose to setup local servers. I have also setup servers in k8s using helm charts.
- Built containers for generic purposes and also specific containers with python programs in them.
- Setting up Jenkins pipelines that fetches data, tests data, run static code testing (sonargube) and then builds a container/binary.
- I have worked with Scrum and with Kanban.
- Continiously supported the software that I have helped develop and setup.
- I have worked with export controlled and nationally classified information.

IT-support

Telia Ogothenburg, Sweden

iii Dec 2019 - June 2020

- I worked in the Technical Support department with customers over the phone, mainly helping customers with problems surrounding their fiber broadband connection and mobile phone services.
- This job gave me knowledge about how to professionally work with customers and colleagues over digital communication.
- The job also knowledge about customer service and working with support sys-

BACKGROUND

Beyond working and being intrested in IT and software development I have worked many jobs during my semesters. I have worked with renting out and setting up tents many summers (Kikiriki AB), This was a job where I had to meet new customers all the time and drove around Gothenburg in a boxtruck. I have worked with customer service at Biltema AB in Hisingsbacka in Gothenburg. I have worked as a referee in floorball.

I have also studied Jazz at Geijer Skolan in Ransäter, Sweden. I mainly studied jazz guitar and played with a small acoustic ensamble and in a big band where i played lead electric guitar.

PERSONALITY TRAITS

Curious





Analytical

Persistent



COGNITIVE SKILLS



Adaptability



Multitasking



Work under pressure





STRENGTHS

Software development Linux and bash scripting Docker compose Docker/podman Leadership kubernetes



KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS



Object-oriented design





MY EDUCATION

BS.c. studies

IT - Security

🚊 2020 - 2023, Blekinge Tekniska Högskola

High School studies 2018

🚊 2015 - 2018, IT-Gymnasiet Göteborg

LANGUAGES I SPEAK

Swedish English German



WHAT I ENJOY

Travel

Guitar

Disc golf

REFERENCES

Upon request